Guide to the photograph album Royal Air Force in Iraq and Sharjah during WWII - Volume II AD.MC.013.v2
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Royal Air Force in Iraq and Sharjah during WWII vol.2
1943-1944
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943
Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
AD.MC.013.v2
76 Leaves - 160 gelatin silver prints, 11 hand-drawn circuitry diagrams, poems and an article entitled "Assyrian Levies - The Battle for Habbaniya 1941"
This is the second of two photograph albums of Royal Air Force Leading Aircraftman C. J. Sainty, who served in Iraq and the Middle East during World War II. The second album shows many pictures of the cities of Baghdad and Basra. The photographs of Ashar, the heart of Basra, show daily life in this ancient city: a boatman, policemen in long coats, a barber, a craftsman, machine shop workers, a bread maker, a copper beater, long hand crafted river boats and a camel caravan. Photographs of a trip to northern Iraq show daily life in the country and endless vistas. The album concludes with various photographs of camp life at the RAF base in Sharjah. Accompanying the two albums are the aircraftman's own manuscript colour drawings – 11 pages comprising an immaculate illustration of the construction of incendiary bomb components and functionality, as well as several poems. Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks.
Box AD-MC-013_v.2
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions at akkasah.org. For access to physical album contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Album purchased from Antiquariat INLIBRIS, Rathausstraße 19, 1010 Wien, Austria, in 2015.
Biographical / Historical
This pair of photograph albums contains a collection of photographs taken by Royal Air Force Leading Aircraftman C.J. Sainty, who served in Iraq and the Middle East during World War II. The photographs were taken in India, Iraq and Sharjah in 1941–43, including the Battle of Habbaniya (1941)
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in December 2015.
Scope and Contents
The first 32 photographs in this collection were taken during Sainty's period in India and show Bombay/Mumbai and the military camp at Colaba. During the Anglo-Iraq war of 1941, Sainty was transferred to the RAF base at Habbaniya and the photographs show Baghdad and the aircraft base and its residents. A special section entitled "The Fortunes of War. May 1941. R.A.F. v Rebels" is devoted to the Battle of Habbaniya and shows British and Iraqi tanks, guns and fallen aircraft, including a German Messerschmidt Bf 110. A few graphic photos of limbs and cadavers in the desert show the less glamorous side of the war. The second album shows many pictures of the cities of Baghdad and Basra. The photographs of Ashar, the heart of Basra, show daily life in this ancient city: a boatman, Arabian policemen in long coats, a barber, a craftsman, machine shop workers, a bread maker, a copper beater, long hand crafted river boats and a camel caravan. Photographs of a trip to northern Iraq show daily life in the country and endless vistas of desolate hills. The album concludes with various photographs of camp life at the RAF base in Sharjah.
Royal Air Force; Iraq; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Mumbai (Bombay), India; Military/Soldiers; Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
- The front cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VII., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_afr01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates
- The front inside cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VII., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_afr02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A group portrait of servicemen in a morning parade at Air Headquarters Iraq., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000001; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Flags; Group Portraits; Parades/Processions; Royal Air Force; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Uniforms; English Writing; Military/Soldiers
- A group portrait of servicemen in Habbaniyah, Iraq., 1943; nyuad_pa000002_n000002; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; English Writing; Military/Soldiers
- Portraits of servicemen., 1942; nyuad_pa000002_n000003; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; English Writing; Military/Soldiers
- Eight photographs including portraits of servicemen and landscapes in Baghdad and Basra., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000004; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Regional/National Dress; Guns; Weapons; Trains; Transportation; Group Portraits; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Baghdad, Iraq; Animals; Deserts; English Writing; Shuaiba/Shaibah, Basra, Iraq; Military/Soldiers
- From left to right: A Christmas menu for the RAF station, a newspaper press, a street barber, workers and two portraits of servicemen., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000005; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Newspapers/Magazines; Shops; Workers; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Men; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; English Writing; Trains; Transportation; Street Vendors; Military/Soldiers
- Photographs taken of street life in Ashar, Iraq., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000006; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Uniforms; Regional/National Dress; Workers; Machines; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Water; Markets; Police; Mosques; Euphrates River; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Signs/Signposts; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Transportation; Cars/Trucks; Markets; Shops
- Six photographs taken on the 25th anniversary of RAF in Habbaniyah, Iraq., 1 April 1943; nyuad_pa000002_n000007; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Uniforms; Parades/Processions; Royal Air Force; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Airplanes; Transportation; Marching Band; Musical Instruments; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from top-left: A group portrait of men and children in Az-Zubayr, two photographs of Ashar Creek, a mosque of the bank of the Euphrates, a woman making bread, a person beating copper and two group portraits of servicemen with two workers., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000008; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Az-Zubayr, Basrah, Iraq; Women; Workers; Food; Rivers; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Mosques; Religious Sites; Euphrates River; Palm Trees; Uniforms; Boats/Ships; Royal Air Force; English Writing; Transportation; Military/Soldiers
- Photographs taken of various scenes in Habbaniyah, Ashar, Baghdad and Shaibah., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000009; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cinema; Lakes; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Camels; Men; Workers; Markets; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Baghdad, Iraq; Deserts; Boys; Children; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; Tents; Palm Trees; Furnishings; Radios; English Writing; Transportation; Shuaiba/Shaibah, Basra, Iraq; Smoking; Animals; Tea/Coffee; Turbans
- Views of Baghdad and Ashar., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000010; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Statues/Sculptures; Palaces; Mosques; Religious Sites; Baghdad, Iraq; Boats/Ships; Women; Group Portraits; Palm Trees; Men; Children; Pottery; Streets/Roads; Bridges; Water; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Al Ashar, Basrah, Iraq; English Writing; Transportation; Agriculture/Farms; Rivers
- Photographs taken of tourist sites including Ancient Babylon, Taq Kasra, mosques, and the Great Pyramids as well as the trans-desert Nairn bus., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000011; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Ctesiphon, Iraq; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Women; Children; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Buses; Deserts; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Food; Police; Doors/Entrances; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Transportation; Mountains/Hills; Cars/Trucks; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Cemeteries; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Four portraits of two men boxing., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000012; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Sports; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Three portraits of two men boxing and four men holding glasses., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000013; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Sports; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Drinks/Beverages; Iraq; Cigarettes; Alcohol; Smoking; Military/Soldiers
- Scenes of Sir Amadir in Southern Kurdistan, North Iraq., August 1943; nyuad_pa000002_n000014; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Men; Individual Portraits; Mosques; Religious Sites; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Turbans; Regional/National Dress
- Clockwise from top left to right: a group portrait of seven men, a mountainside, and portraits of a man at the Duraji stream in Iraq., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000015; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Water; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Hats; English Writing; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from top left to right: a mountain landscape, a man raking, children at the Duraji stream in Iraq, and men drinking tea., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000016; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Men; Group Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Water; Waterfalls; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boys; Individual Portraits; Royal Air Force; Tea/Coffee; Children; Agriculture/Farms; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from top left: A group of men collecting water, servicemen with a villager from Duri, shelters on the landscape, and the main street of the village, Amadir (Amadiya)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000017; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Mountains/Hills; Food; Hats; Men; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Streets/Roads; Water; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Regional/National Dress; Military/Soldiers
- Scenes of an expedition through the mountains., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000018; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Mountains/Hills; Group Portraits; Water; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Individual Portraits; Iraq; Donkeys; Animals; Hats; Boys; Children; Uniforms; Streets/Roads; Transportation; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from top left: a man at a watering hole, a street view of Mosul, a man on a mule in Amadir (Amadiya), and a man at a watering hole., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000019; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Horses; Animals; Donkeys; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Mosul, Iraq; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Water; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Buildings; Restaurants/bars; Arabic Writing; Shops; Electricity; Military/Soldiers
- Views of servicemen on a mountain climbing expedition., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000020; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Donkeys; Animals; Transportation; Mountains/Hills; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Boys; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Water; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Tents; Regional/National Dress; Military/Soldiers; Children
- Views of servicemen on a mountain climbing expedition., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000021; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Donkeys; Animals; Boys; Children; Men; Swimming; Group Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Individual Portraits; Cattle/Cows; Waterfalls; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Bridges; Streets/Roads; Uniforms; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Military/Soldiers
- Views of servicemen on a mountain climbing expedition., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000022; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Mountains/Hills; Tents; Boys; Individual Portraits; Children; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Landscapes
- Two photographs of a cinema in Sharjah [labeled Saudi Arabia] and group portraits of servicemen., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000023; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Royal Air Force; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Saudi Arabia; Uniforms; Men; Airplanes; Cinema; English Writing; Transportation; Military/Soldiers
- Group portraits of servicemen in Masirah and Sharjah, and the base camp in Sharjah., 1943; nyuad_pa000002_n000024; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airplanes; Masirah Island, Oman; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Saudi Arabia; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Alcohol; Woodwind Instruments; Musical Instruments; Furnishings; English Writing; Transportation; Christmas; Military/Soldiers
- Portraits of servicemen, a man standing with a child and the interior of the NAAFI in Sharjah., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000025; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Costumes; Individual Portraits; Royal Air Force; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Saudi Arabia; Boys; Children; Cigarettes; Smoking; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Performing Arts; Sports; Furnishings; Musical Instruments; Military/Soldiers
- From top left clockwise: various group portraits of servicemen, a base camp, and a portrait of a man., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000026; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Mountains/Hills; Facial Hair; Iraq; Buildings; Military/Soldiers
- Multiple group portraits of servicemen in their camp., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000027; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Group Portraits; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Children; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Coast; Military/Soldiers
- Group portraits of servicemen and a plane., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000028; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Men; Airplanes; Transportation; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000029; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Saudi Arabia
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_n000030; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- The inside back cover of the album., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- The back cover of the album., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A pamphlet about life in Habbaniyah, Iraq (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk03_z01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Printed Materials; English Writing; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Newspapers/Magazines
- A pamphlet about life in Habbaniyah, Iraq (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk03_z02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Printed Materials; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; English Writing; Newspapers/Magazines
- A pamphlet about life in Habbaniyah, Iraq (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk03_z03; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A pamphlet about life in Habbaniyah, Iraq (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk03_z04; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Printed Materials; English Writing; Newspapers/Magazines
- A diagram of an incendiary bomb container., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  English Writing; Printed Materials; Iraq; Royal Air Force
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq
- A circuit diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z03; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Printed Materials; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z04; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A circuit diagram of a way selector switch box., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z05; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Printed Materials; Iraq; English Writing; Royal Air Force
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z06; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Diagrams of Jettison switches., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z07; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Printed Materials; English Writing; Royal Air Force
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z08; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Diagrams of a switch box., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z09; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z10; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z11; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Printed Materials; Royal Air Force; English Writing
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z12; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A circuit diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z13; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z14; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A Jettison box diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z15; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z16; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A Jettison box diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z17; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Printed Materials; Iraq; Royal Air Force; English Writing
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z18; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A Jettison box diagram., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z19; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk04_z20; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A handwritten poem by C. J. Sainty., 22 December 1943; nyuad_pa000002_zbk05_z01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Printed Materials; English Writing; Poetry; Signatures
- A poem entitled Lido of the East (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk06_z01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Printed Materials; Poetry; English Writing
- Blank page., Circa 1943 - 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk06_z02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
- A poem entitled Men England Forget! (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., June 1944; nyuad_pa000002_zbk07_z01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD-MC-013_v.2)
  Iraq; Poetry; Printed Materials; English Writing; Masirah Island, Oman